# **BRIAN BEHRENS**

Principal Software Engineer

(206) 617-0153 brian@brainbrian.com brainbrian.com

4750 Beloit Ave Culver City, CA 90291

For a more detailed resume visit <u>brainbrian.com/resume</u> or find me at <u>linkedin.com/in/brianbehrens</u>

#### **PROFILE**

I'm Brian Behrens, a developer living in Los Angeles, CA. I have been building interactive projects professionally since 2003. The bulk of my career has been centered around websites, social campaigns and web-based applications. I have focused heavily on interaction design, web standards, usability, animation, video, e-commerce and application architecture. My passion for technology is ever-evolving and I enjoy new challenges. Behind it all, I'm a problem solver who likes telling stories. In my free time you'll find me surfing, taking photos, exploring code and/or spending time with my wife and dogs.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Principal Software Engineer, VideoAmp; Santa Monica, CA — 2018-Present Starting at VideoAmp on the DesignOps team, we focused on building our design system. This was built using TypeScript, React, Jest, Cypress, Percy, Codecov, D3 and more. I have since transitioned to a principal role, working as a full-stack engineer. I now deliver features and shared code in both our front and backend services using Node.js, TypeScript, React, hapi, Postgres, Snowflake and various AWS services like SQS and SNS. I help lead guild meetings and mentor other engineers.

Software Engineer - Front End, REI; Kent, WA (100% remote) — 2017-2018

Lead front end software engineer for the Classes/Events and Adventures team. Work in a continuous integrated environment with Docker, Java, Jenkins and more. Spend most of my time updating our front end systems to be written in ES6 linting standards with Vue.js components. Use build tools like webpack and dependency management on the front end is done via our private NPM repository. Unit test our shared modules with Mocha and Chai.

### Senior Interactive Developer, POP; Seattle, WA — 2015-2017

Second time working at POP. Previously wrote a large amount of ActionScript 3, building applications and animations for various clients. This time I focused heavily on JavaScript. Used Node.js on almost every project integrating Grunt, Gulp or webpack for build tools. Used frameworks/libraries like React, Angular, GreenSock, jQuery, ScrollMagic and many others. Created animations in both CSS and JavaScript. Led various server integrations, API and database development, Docker configuration and other backend duties. Developed within Node.js, Apache, .NET and AWS environments.

Senior Web Developer, Mervin Manufacturing; Seattle, WA — 2012-2015

Senior Interface Developer, Blast Radius; Seattle, WA - 2011-2012

Senior Interactive Developer, POP; Seattle, WA - 2008-2011

### **EDUCATION**

Milwaukee Area Technical College, Milwaukee, WI - 2001-2005

Associates Degree in Television & Video Production (2001-2003) Associates Degree in Visual Communications (2003-2005)

## **SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, React, Vue.js, webpack, Preprocessors, Babel, SQL, Postgres, Snowflake, Python, PHP, MySQL, NoSQL, Source Control (Git & SVN), WordPress, JSON, XML, Social APIs, JS Libraries (Underscore, GreenSock), Agile Methodology, Adobe Creative Cloud, Project Estimation/Planning, Managing Teams, Video and Photography